# **CAMERON PEPPER**

| ① 19 Singer Court, Toronto, ON, M2K 0B2 | ② (705) 349 - 1434 | ™ cameronpep@gmail.com |

### **SUMMARY**

Engineer in Training with over four years of professional experience. Holds a BESc. in chemical engineering. Specializes in the analysis of process trends and driving operational efficiencies. Track record for successfully identifying opportunities for continuous improvement for clients. Experience in construction inspection, manufacturing, process improvement and cost analysis.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Highway Construction Inspector - AECOM, 2019 - present

- Supervise quality assurance testing and inspect structures, grading, granular, concrete, asphalt, electrical and all other construction activities.
- Identify and document construction and quality control deficiencies (from applicable contract and standard specifications).
- Become familiar with and ensure stakeholders' compliance with contract documents, specifications, standards, manufacturers' material specifications, and special provisions.

### Associate Estimator – Fowler Construction Company Limited, 2016 - 2018

- Prepare tender submissions for capital projects, including writing technical proposals to outline construction schedules, equipment logistics and allocation.
- Investigate engineering design alternatives and cost saving optimizations, maintain safety standards, ensure quality control
  and efficiency of company's asphalt production plant.
- Perform quantity takeoffs from engineering plans to manage resources for capital projects.
- Monitor, collect and analyze market data to identify business expansion opportunities.

#### Achievements:

April '17 – Individually recognized for safety protocol assessments performed during that fiscal year.

April '18 – Recognized for new historical record capture process for continuous improvement.

# Pre-sales Network Engineer in Training - Cisco Systems, 2015

- Build, configure and maintain the networking lab in Cisco's Toronto office.
- Assist senior engineers with building and configuring proof of concepts.
- Maximize lab utilization and availability by monitoring performance and scheduling upgrades to showcase the latest software/hardware features.
- Assist in successful execution of major projects such as: The Bell Let's Talk campaign, 2015 Pan Am and Parapan Am Games
  in Toronto, complete relocation of the Cisco networking lab

#### Achievements

March '15 – One of two department associates selected to enable Cisco logistics as the official IT and communications provider of the Toronto 2015 Pan Am and Parapan Am Games.

# Construction Inspector and Survey Technician – Tulloch Engineering, Summer contracts 2012 - 2014

- Manage change orders and other formal documentation to support various capital projects.
- Review validity of construction claims and prepare mathematical and causal analysis on conditions to quantify each claim.
- Utilize field equipment (total stations, Real-Time Kinematic GPS systems, and mobile LiDAR) and digital survey software to provide cadastral, engineering, and control survey services.

#### Achievements:

March '14 – Oversaw technical documentation and logistics surrounding construction of a \$16M international tunnel facility for the Canadian Border Services Agency.

## Junior Chemical Engineer in Training – Kimberly Clark, Summer contract 2011

- Conduct quality control testing, studies and technical reports on manufacturing options for new or improved products and components.
- Evaluate equipment options, understand capability to deliver product features, and optimize process efficiency and cost.
- Tabulate and present weekly manufacturing metrics to the engineering, manufacturing and packaging teams to provide an
  overall understanding of total process capability to produce products to specification and cost targets.

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Engineering Science – Chemical Engineering, 2014 Dean's Honor List, 2011 University of Western Ontario, London, ON